翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
Now, like classes, arrays are going to be almost always instantiated using the new keyword.
与类相似，数组总是使用 new 关键字实例化
So for strings, we saw you don't have to use new.
而字符串不必使用 new
With arrays, it's going to be new most of the time.
数组大部分时间都使用 new
So there's three notations for defining arrays in Java.
在 Java 中有三种定义数组的记号
And the first tier is just a simple creation of an array,
第一层只是简单地创建一个数组
but not specifying the values that go in an array.
但不指定数组中的值
So this first syntax says the variable y, which I'm assuming has been declared earlier,
第一种语法表示，变量 y，假设已经声明过了
I want to put in that 64-bit box the address of an array I'm now creating.
我将创建的数组地址放入64位盒子中
That array will consist of three boxes of 32 bits each,
该数组由三个盒子组成，每个盒子32位
along with a length, three.
还有一个长度3
And Java, when you create an array,
Java 中当你创建数组时
it will get a default value.
它将获得默认值
And we'll see in the visualization what that means exactly.
我们将在可视化中看到这到底意味着什么
In the other kind of notation-- or sorry, the second type of notation
第二种记号中
is to say x equals new int and then here have the actual values you want to put in there by default.
x = new int，这里默认有你想放的实际数值
So in this case, we're not explicitly stating the size of the array, but Java's able.
在这种情况下，我们没有明确说明数组的大小，但 Java...
It's pretty smart, figures it out.
它很聪明，算出来了
It says, ah, you want an array of size five,
它知道你想要一个大小为5的数组
and it puts these values in instead of the default value.
它会将这些值放入，而不是默认赋值
Now, note that when you create an array in Java,
现在请注意，当你在 Java 中创建数组时
you always get a default value.
你始终会获得默认值
So if you say new int one million, it's going to set aside a million boxes,
如果 new int 一百万，它会留出一百万个盒子
and it's going to write a bunch of zeros if it's all ints.
如果是整数数组会全写入0
So there's a little bit of overhead associated with creating arrays in Java.
因此在 Java 中创建数组会带来一些开销
All right, so next up, we have our final and somewhat strange syntax.
接下来，我们看最后一个有点奇怪的语法
This one is just like the one above,
这个和上面的一样
except we don't do new int.
只不过不用 new int
And what's sort of funny about this is it only works when you're also declaring a variable at the same time.
有趣的是，只有当你同时声明了一个变量，它才会起作用
So if I say int bracket w,
所以 int[] w
that allows me, because I'm declaring right now, to instantiate without the new int keyword.
这是允许的，因为我正在声明，在没有 new int 的情况下进行实例化
Why is it this way?
为什么？
I don't know, but that's the thing to do.
我不知道，但就是这样
So if you like this notation, be aware that you can't use it with an already declared variable.
如果你喜欢这种表示法，注意不能将其与已声明的变量一起使用
So each of these notations, they all do the same thing.
每种记号都在做相同的事
They create an array which has some length
它们创建一个具有一定长度的数组
and it has N boxes, where N is the length.
它有 N 个盒子，其中 N 是长度
For those of you curious about what's happening under the hood,
如果你好奇内部的原理
you might imagine that an array is,
可以想象一个数组是
well, maybe it's 32 bits for the length plus k bits per box, for a total of 32 plus k times N bits for an array.
长度32位加每个盒子 k 位，每个数组总共 (32+k×N) 位
But it turns out that in typical implementations,
但事实证明，在典型的实现中
it's actually a little more.
会多一点
I have a little note in the bottom right corner,
右下角有一个小笔记
and there's some reading in our optional textbook
选修教材里有一些阅读材料
if you're curious, but not important for 61B.
好奇可以看看，但对61B 来说并不重要
So let's work through an example.
看一个例子
So this is an example where I think that you, given what you saw in project zero and in this lecture,
这个例子，鉴于你在项目0和本节课中学到的
you could do every step of this
你可以完成每一步
and draw a nice box and pointer diagram, except maybe this last step here.
画一个漂亮的盒子指针图，也许除了这里的最后一步
So let's run through this example.
让我们来看一下这个例子
And you can follow along and try and guess what's going to happen.
试着猜猜会发生什么
Now, I'm going to get two options.
现在我有两个选项
I want this so that things look nice and we don't get weird--
选择这个会比较好看一点，不会感到奇怪
we did this last time.
上次就这么做了
So make sure that it looks more like a box and pointer diagram.
为了确保它看起来更像是盒子指针图
I'm also going to enable this option so that strings show their true nature.
我还将启用此选项，以便字符串显示其真实性质
So if you're curious what these do,
如果你好奇这些的作用
you can take them away and see what's different, but whatever.
你可以取消选择，看看有什么不同
This is just so that the diagram it generates
这只是为了使它生成的图
is consistent with our box and pointer notation.
与我们的盒子指针符号一致
So the code begins.
代码开始了
Int bracket z.
int[] z
What does that do?
那是做什么的？
Well, that's going to create a box of how many bits?
这将创建一个多少位的盒子？
64.
And what goes in there?
里面装的是什么？
An address.
一个地址
Remember, there are only nine things in Java, types.
请记住 Java 中只有九种类型
There are the eight primitive types and then references to anything.
八种基本类型，和对任何内容的引用
This is a reference to an int array.
这是对整型数组的引用
So you get 64 bits,
所以得到64位
and into that array, we write a bunch of zeros, which we call null for short.
在该数组中，我们写入一串0，简称为 null
So we have 64 bits here, all zeros.
所以这里有64位，全是0
Now in the visualizer, we also, at this point, get two more boxes, x and y, which will be 64 bits.
在 visualizer 中，我们此时得到两个64位的盒子，x 和 y
But the visualizer, as designed by Philip Guo, does not show those boxes.
但是 Philip Guo 设计的 visualizer 并没有显示这些盒子
But you can imagine they're there.
你可以想象它们在那里
So we do x equals new int.
执行 x = new int
We get our 64-bit box x, and we fill it with 64 bits.
我们得到64位盒子 x，并用64位填充它
What goes in those bits?
填充的什么呢？
Why, the address, as returned by the new function.
是 new 功能返回的地址
What does the new function do?
new 有什么作用？
Well, it's going to go find someplace in memory for five integers to live.
它会在内存中找个地方存放五个整数
Here they are.
它们在这
So 32 bits for each one.
每个32位
And x is going to record the location in memory of this whole box.
x 将记录整个盒子在内存中的位置
Now, notice that the visualizer does not explicitly show the integer that stores the length of an array,
注意 visualizer 并没有明确显示存储数组长度的整数
though it does, nonetheless, exist, at least in a typical implementation of Java.
尽管它在 Java 的典型实现中确实存在
So you can imagine there's a little five up here,
你可以想象上面有个5
but not shown.
但没显示
Now, when I say y equals x, what does this do?
y = x 是做什么的？
We have this box over here that has 64 bits in it.
在这有个64位的盒子
And of course, the thing you do whenever you say y equals x is what?
y = x 时，做的事情是什么？
Copy the bits.
复制位
Nothing else.
没别的了
So when we copy the bits, well, our visual metaphor says we should draw an arrow to the same object,
当我们复制位时，视觉上应该画一个箭头指向同一个对象
and there you have it.
现在已经有了
Now we're going to take x
现在我们要用 x
and we're going to replace these bits here with the address as returned by this next call to new.
我们将用下一次调用 new 所返回的地址来替换这些位
So this is, again, array of size five,
这又是大小为5的数组
and now x gets the bits corresponding to the address of x.
x 获得相对应的地址的位
Next, we have y equals new int 3.
接下来，y = new int[3]
And so what that means is we're going to throw away these bits
这意味着我们要扔掉这些位
and replace them with the address of a new array of size three.
并用大小为3的新数组的地址替换它们
So there's a couple interesting things here.
这里有几件有趣的事
One of them is that the visualizer is going to make this disappear.
其中之一就是 visualizer 会让这些东西消失
So it's gone, right?
不见了，对吧？
And it kind of reorganizes for us.
重组一下
But the array that's one, two, three, four, five,
数组是1，2，3，4，5
it's just gone forever.
一去不复返了
We can never get it back.
再也拿不回来了
That's what I mean by an object is anonymous.
这就是我所说的匿名对象
We lose the reference.
我们失去了引用
That's just it.
就这样了
We'll never see that array again.
我们再也见不到那个数组了
Garbage collection.
垃圾回收
Next step, then, the other thing that was interesting is that we've got an array of size three.
另一件有趣的事情是，我们得到了一个大小为3的数组
In this case, it's all zeros.
在这种情况下都是0
Why zeros?
为什么是0？
Well, in Java, when you create an array,
在 Java 中，当你创建一个数组时
you always get default values.
始终会获得默认值
Much like how with a class, as we saw before,
就像之前课上的一样
you get a bunch of default values for every instance variable.
每个实例变量都会得到默认值
So these are my default values, which for an integer is zero.
这些是我的默认值，整数的默认值是0
This is just for fun.
很有趣
So when I run this line, I get an array of size zero,
运行这行得到一个大小为0的数组
so there are no boxes and an int, presumably, that says zero somewhere.
所以没有盒子和整数，估计某处为0
And so it just points at this thing.
它只是指向这个东西
If I want to get the length of an array,
如果我想要获取数组的长度
I can actually use dot length.
实际上可以使用 .length
So you can think of it as an array is like a class,
把一个数组想象成一个类
in a way, that has an instance variable, kind of, that is called length.
它有一个叫 length 的实例变量
And so when I say int xl equals x.length, it accesses this--
int xL = x.length，它访问...
let's see. Yeah, this is x.
访问 x
It accesses the secret five we cannot see,
它进入我们看不到的5
and it copies those bits.
复制这些位
So it had a five up here.
这上面有5
We copy them.
复制它
We had a five.
得到5
Now, we have creating a string array.
现在我们创建了一个字符串数组
So a challenge for you to ponder,
一个需要深思熟虑的挑战是
how many boxes get made?
制作了多少盒子？
OK, that one's probably pretty easy.
也许很简单
And how many bits are in each box?
那么每个盒子里有多少位？
Zero?
0？
There's no strings here.
这里没有字符串
What do you think?
你觉得呢？
And you might try and guess what the default value will be.
你可能会尝试猜测默认值是什么
Well, I'll spoil it for you.
我来给你扫兴
What you get is six boxes, and each one's 64 bits.
你得到的是6个盒子，每个盒子64位
And each one can hold what?
每个装什么呢？
I want you to answer that question yourself awkwardly.
我要你自己笨拙地回答这个问题
I don't care if your roommate's watching you,
我不在乎你的室友是否在看着你
whatever, and you have ear buds in.
管他呢，你还戴着耳塞
You're just going to say out loud your answer,
你只要大声说出答案
and they'll think you're weird.
他们会觉得你很怪异
OK, string references.
字符串引用
That's correct or not correct, depending on what you said.
正确与否取决于你说了什么
So what we've got here now is six boxes, 64 bits each.
我们现在有6个盒子，每个盒子64位
They hold string references, and the default value is all zeros, which is null.
它们保存字符串引用，默认值为全0，即 null
So then we go to the box and we say--
我们来到盒子
or we going to box four of this array.
我们来到4号盒子
So s points at this whole thing.
这就是整件事的关键
We say go four slots over, and now we're waiting and looking at the 64 bits.
我们来到4号槽， 等待并查看64位
We're going to assign them to ketchup.
我们要把它分派给 ketchup
What is ketchup?
ketchup 是什么？
Well, we saw before that we can instantiate strings with quotes,
前面看到过，我们可以用引号实例化字符串
so in this case, we basically call new secretly without seeing it.
这种情况下，我们基本上是在看不到的地方调用 new
So what that will do is a new string is created,
这将会创建一个新的字符串
its address is returned, and arrow points at it.
返回它的地址，并且箭头指向它
How about this line?
这行呢？
So I think that if you came from 61A, 61S, or, really, any programming course,
如果你来自61A、61S 或者任何编程课程
this, I hope, you can figure out.
我希望你能弄清楚
So try and figure out what's going to happen from this one.
试着弄清楚这一次会发生什么
So Java, what it will do is this is not a value.
Java 它要做的是，这不是一个值
It's going to evaluate each of these things.
它将评估每个东西
It needs to compute this difference.
需要计算这个差值
So it's first going to go to x3.
所以首先要转到 x3
Do, do, do, do, four.
x1, do, do, two.
x1 是 2
Now, it's going to say 4 minus 2 is 2.
现在4-2=2
So it'll go to s2, and it'll set this equal to the address of a new string, muffins.
因此它将转到s2，并将其设置为新字符串 muffins 的地址
Next, we'll create an int array b.
接下来创建一个整型数组 b
That one's not very interesting.
这个不是很有趣
It's just the same as we've done before.
和以前的一样
But now we have this extra little call,
但现在有一个额外的调用
system.arraycopy, I'll be explaining in just a moment.
System.arraycopy，我稍后会解释
So what system.arraycopy does, though,
System.arraycopy 的作用是
is it copies from array b to array x.
从数组 b 复制到数组 x
And it starts at position zero of b,
它从 b 的位置0开始
and it copies to position three of x.
复制到 x 的位置3
And I find the syntax a little hard to remember.
我觉得语法有点难记
I always have to look it up every semester.
每学期都要查一查
But basically, it-- and it's going to copy two of those numbers.
但基本上，它会复制其中的两个数字
So in other words, starting from zero of b, going two slots over.
换句话说，从b的0开始，移动两个槽
These are the ones I want to copy.
这些就是我想复制的
I'm going to go to this location and copy them here.
我要到这个地方，把它们复制到这里
So after I run that, you'll see 9, 10 up here, up there.
所以运行后，那里变成9和10
So that's basic array code.
这就是基本的数组代码
Let's talk a little bit more about array copy.
再多讨论一下数组的复制
So, actually, the first question we ask ourselves is, why would we ever want to make a copy of an array?
第一个问题，我们为什么要复制一个数组？
Well, it's not enough just to say, for example,
举个例子，光说是不够的
y equals x, right?
y = x 对吗？
This just says I'm copying the address of an array from one variable to another.
这只是说明我正在将数组的地址从一个变量复制到另一个变量
This is two references to the same array.
这是对同一数组的两个引用
Similarly, suppose we're trying to write a nondestructive array function that takes an array and, say,
类似地，假设我们试图编写一个非破坏性的数组函数，该函数接受一个数组
squares each of its elements.
每个元素取平方
Whenever you give that function an array reference,
当你为函数提供数据引用时
it gets an actual reference to the original array.
它获取对原始数组的实际引用
So I have a main, financial tax software, da, da, da.
假设我有一个财务税务软件 XXX
I don't know why you're squaring numbers in tax software, but anyway.
我不知道你为什么要在税务软件里做平方，但不管怎样
I give my precious array, me, to someone else to go do squaring,
我把我珍贵的数组，给别人去做平方
and they claim to be doing it non-destructively.
他们声称这样做是非破坏性的
They better have some way to make a copy of an array,
他们最好有办法复制一个数组
otherwise they're breaking my array.
否则会破坏我的数组
Because if it says nondestructive, it better be that way.
因为如果它说是非破坏性的，最好这样
So there's two ways to make a copy.
有两种方法可以复制
One is do an item-by-item copy.
一种是逐项复制
Just write a loop.
写个循环就行
While i is less than x.length, y of i equals x of i.
while (i < x.length)，y[i] = x[i]
Now, the alternate approach is to use array copy.
另一种方法是使用数组复制
And this function takes five parameters.
该函数接受5个参数
So when I see system.arraycopy, it says copy from the array b starting at index zero to the destination array x, starting at x's position three.
System.arraycopy 从数组 b 的0索引开始复制到目标数组 x 的3索引
And by the way, copy two of those.
复制两个
So in slice notation, if you know Python,
如果了解 Python，在切片表示中
it would be something like this.
应该这样
And if you've never seen slice notation,
如果你从未见过切片表示法
do not worry about it.
别担心
So array copy, what's the advantage of using it versus a loop?
数组复制与循环相比有什么优势呢？
Well, it's probably going to be faster, particularly for large arrays,
它可能会更快，特别是对于大型数组
because Java interpreter is closer to the hardware.
因为 Java 解释器更接近硬件
So it can take advantage of knowledge about how things truly work that you, as a Java programmer, cannot.
它可以利用相关事物真正运作的知识，而你作为一个 Java 程序员却不能
The other reason is the code is a bit more compact,
另一个原因是代码更紧凑
and if somebody knows what this means,
有的人知道这是什么意思
it can be easier to read than looking at a loop.
它可能比循环更易读
But one could also argue it's harder to read,
但也有人可能会争辩说，它更难读
because you have to remember what all these parameters do.
因为你必须记住所有参数的作用
So I'll leave it to your judgment which you think seems easier to read.
你自己判断哪个更易读
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）